Alex Carroll

San Diego, CA

alex@alexcarroll.dev

A seasoned full-stack engineer with a passion for good design and user experience. I have experience in the latest javascript tools, including Angular and React on the front-end, and Node.js on the back-end, and strive to write clean, tested, and accessible code. For the last four years I have been successfully working remotely as an individual contributor and am looking forward to a role where I can help a team bring ideas to reality.

Experience

Senior Software Engineer

Data Recognition Corporation | Remote | Nov 2017-Present

Lead full-stack development of Central Office, a suite of applications to manage testing devices for schools and testing facilities, with up to 15,000 requests/minute from managed devices supporting 1.4 million daily, and 300,000 concurrent users with well-tested and accessible code.

- Lead full-stack development work on an Agile, cross-functional team mainly using Angular, Node.js, Sails.js, Mocha, and deployed to AWS. Provide estimates for new features and bug fixes.
- Support mission critical applications on Windows, Linux, and Mac.
- Participate in agile functions: sprint planning and retrospectives, backlog grooming, sprint refinements, release demos, and story pointing.
- Work with DevOps, business process managers, database administrators, product owners, and support engineers to ensure customer satisfaction.
- Manage, build, and deploy jobs through Jenkins and Puppet.

Software Engineer

IBM | Austin, TX and Remote | Jan 2015–Nov 2017

Developer for several high visibility products in IBM Design including Bluemix: a PaaS solution, Planning Analytics: a financial tool for multinational corporations, and Watson Analytics as a lead developer on the marketing website.

- Cultivated relationships with distributed, multi-national teammates.
- Resource for Accessibility concerns and consulted on WCAG 2.0 AA.
- Led front-end development in Agile teams, planned sprints, performed code reviews
- Mentored junior developers. Identified a need for a collaborative learning environment for front-end developers leading to the creation, funding procurement, development and implementation of a successful program called FEDucation.
- Full-stack developer on both the MEAN and MERN stacks and other technologies.

Interactive Developer

Target Corporation | Minneapolis, MN | Sept 2011–Nov 2011 (contractor) Nov 2011–Dec 2014 (employee)

Developer for Target's inhouse marketing team, Target Creative. Lead developer for www.target.ca (now sunsetted), Target Cartwheel, Target Registry, contributing developer on several internal projects to enhance www.target.com. Resource for accessibility standards.

- Led work effort on high-touch and highly trafficked websites and applications with up to 35 million unique weekly users.
- Became expert on WCAG 2.0 AA web accessibility standards and worked with accessibility teams to ensure all applications met those standards.
- Increased return trips and total purchases for users of Target Cartwheel.
- Developed code using jQuery, Backbone, Node.js, SCSS, and others.

Education

B.A.S, with honors, Web Design & Interactive Media, Art Institutes International - Minnesota, 2011